# ZACH MASON

## SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack, front-end leaning web developer with a Masters in Teaching. I am experienced with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node.js), SQL, Ruby on Rails, Marketo, C#, Angular, React Native, and more. When I'm not coding, I'm producing music, traveling, and spending time with my dog and

## **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, C#, SQL

#### FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES:

NodeJS, Express, ReactJS, jQuery, Boostrap, Rails

DATABASES: SQL, MongoDB OTHER SKILLS: Research, Collaboration, Leadership, Conflict Resolution, Teaching

## **EDUCATION**

#### **General Assembly**

Web Development Immersive 2016 ·Built projects utilizing JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, AngularJS, SQL, Ruby on Rails

#### **Seattle University**

Masters in Teaching 2013

• Endorsements: History & Social Studies

#### Pepperdine University

B.A. History 2008

• Studied abroad in Heidelberg, Germany (2005 - 2006)

## **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Rosetta Stone, Web Developer, Seattle, WA

Aug. 2018 - Current

Developing website modules using the ReactJS framework (JSX, Less, ES6) with E&E team at Rosetta Stone. Building components (Nav, Filter, Search), unit testing, continuous integration, A/B testing, for the business and education portal, utilizing technologies: GatsbyJS, Algolia, Jenkins, Git, and select NPM packages.

#### The Box Maker / Fantastapack, Full Stack Developer, Kent, WA

Mar. 2018 - Aug. 2018

Built and maintained APIs using Google Cloud, NodeJS, ExpressJS, SQL, PostgreSQL. Built and continuously integrated tools utilizing ReactJS and React-Redux for client submissions. Updated Fantastapack website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, expedited and validated submitted customer and vendor orders via API routing, middleware, and modular services.

#### Catalysis, Jr. Front End Developer, Seattle, WA

Developed responsive Microsoft emails and landing webpages using ExactTarget, Marketo and technologies such as HTML, CSS, AmpScript, and JavaScript. Deployed collaborative quick iterations of builds involving: QAing, unit testing, and debugging in an agile environment in order to deliver marketing promotions and newsletters. Built C# apps as growth goals and React Native with Redux apps personally.

#### General Assembly Immersive, Web Developer, Seattle, WA

July 2016 - Oct. 2016

12 week immersive course with 480 hours of instruction, 5 sprint development projects in an agile environment. Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MEAN stack (MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, NodeJS), SQL, Ruby on Rails.

#### Kent School District, Social Studies Teacher, Kent, WA

Aug. 2015 - June 2016

Taught 9th grade Contemporary World History & 11th grade US History. Cycle of Inquiry Growth Goal met by 90% of students; writing with evidence. Collaborated with PLC to design unit lesson plans and assessments; analyzed data.

#### Bellevue School District, Substitute Teacher, Bellevue, WA

Aug. 2013 - June 2015

Instructed 4-12th grade History, English, Humanities, Government, & Economics.

#### EFL Institute, English Teacher, Daegu, South Korea

July 2009 - July 2010

Managed and taught K-8th grade Korean students in reading, writing, & English.

## **PROJECTS**

#### Validation Service API

May 2018 - June 2018

Built RESTful API using NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL, Gcloud. This API creates and / or updates data depending on success of third party vendor project's async flow into existing API, and then uses a cron job to hit a GET route to return falsey unsuccessful orders in a 2 hour span. All falsey orders are then emailed out to customer support via Mailgun, guaranteeing Fantastapack no missing orders.

#### React Native with Redux Mobile Manager App

Ian. 2018 - Feb. 2018

A Working React-Native app using Redux, Firebase, Security Features, allows a manager or HR to have an editable employee list and can create, read, edit, delete list of employees (CRUD). Allows employer to text employees.

#### Consignment Shop App

Aug. 2017 - Oct. 2017

A C# App that can be used by consignment shops to run their business. Includes list of vendor, items, commission, etc.

#### Marvel Hero Explorer

Mar. 2017 - Apr. 2017

A Windows 10 App Marvel Hero App using C#, XAML, and the Marvel Hero API

### Portfolio

Sept. 2016

My personal portfolio. Contains links to all projects, personal bio, resume, and contact. Link: https://zaturnvalley.github.io/Portfolio/

Aug. 2016

A full stack app that allows you to search a video game API and rate / review games.

Used HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, SQL, Sequelize, Express, AJAX, Bcrypt, EJS & EJS Layouts, Passport. Link: http://gameranker.herokuapp.com/

#### Chat Emoji

Sept. 2016

A full-stack Ruby on Rails web socket app designed by a team of 4 collaboratively. The app's focus centered around helping users to find and live chat with like-minded patrons. Technologies Used: Ruby on Rails + Active Record, Web Socket / Action Cable, User Authentication, HTML / CSS, Postgres, CoffeeScript, Wireframes, Emoji Picker Gem, and Bcrypt.